Timi Bolaji Idowu

Lagos State, Nigeria



idowu.durotimi@gmail.com



08101590442, 09056719928



linkedin.com/in/timi-bolaji-idowu-077258109

Summary

As a Technical Support Engineer, I have honed my problem-solving skills, which I believe will serve me well as a Software Engineer. I am experienced in analyzing complex technical issues and developing creative solutions to address them. This ability will be invaluable as I work to design and build software solutions for clients.

In addition to my problem-solving skills, I have acquired extensive knowledge of Java Spring Boot Framework, and Restful API using JWT or Passport Authentication, VueJs, GitHub, Docker, BitBucket, MySQL, JUnit. I am selfdriven, result-oriented, enthusiastic, and always ready to learn new technologies.

Experience

Java Software Engineer

OnePipe

Jan 2023 - Present (5 months)

- Developing and implementing Java Based Applications
- Aligning application design with business goals
- Developing and testing software
- Recommending changes to existing Java infrastructure

Technical & Operations Support

OnePipe

Apr 2022 - Mar 2023 (1 year)

- Researched, diagnosed, troubleshoot, and identified solutions to resolve technical issues.
- Followed standard procedures for proper escalation of unresolved issues to the appropriate internal/external teams
- Carried out root cause analysis of incidents with aim of putting measures in place to forestall reoccurrence
- Provided prompt and accurate feedback to customers.
- Documented knowledge in the form of knowledge base technical notes and articles.

Intern - Java Developer

Identiko Integrated Solutions

Jan 2022 - Apr 2022 (4 months)

Sidel Hustin Laravel Developer

Side Hustle

Oct 2021 - Dec 2021 (3 months)



Unified Payment Services Limited

Apr 2017 - Dec 2021 (4 years 9 months)

- Processing Financial Transactions Files from Card Schemes
- Processing POS Data Extracts to Visa & MasterCard

Processing of Chargebacks and Merchandise Return Transactions

- POS Merchandise Registration
- Generation of reports (Daily, Weekly, Monthly, and Quarterly) as demanded via database with SQL scripts
- Operator of Hourly Settlement Service
- Receive and make calls regarding queries on transactions
- Internal & External Customer Support

Education



Ladoke Akintola University of Technology

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science 2018 - 2021

Innovation Institute of Information Technology, Akure, Ondo State.

OND, Computer Software Engineering 2013 - 2015

🄊 Adeniran Ogunsanya College of Education, Otto, Ijanikin, Badagry, Lagos

NCE, Economics/Mathematics

2010 - 2013

Licenses & Certifications



Jobberman Soft Training Skills - Jobberman Nigeria

Backend Development (Laravel) - Side Hustle SH-IT-0099123

ISO/IEC 27001:2013 & ISO/IEC 27701:2019 Implementer and Internal Auditor Course - Tenol Alpha

Skills

Nuxt.js • Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD) • Docker • Customer Success • Customer Relationship Management (CRM) • Freshdesk • Java • Spring Boot • Spring Security • MySQL